CRYSTAL L. YOUNG

Software Engineer

LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/crystallynnyoung

GITHUB: https://github.com/Catastrophie

EMAIL: crystalyoung92@gmail.com PORTFOLIO: catastrophie.github.com

Published Works

Call Of Duty Modern Warfare 2

2022-2023

Network telemetry and UI involved systems Associate Software Engineer

Studio specific pipeline programs • C++ • High Moon Studios Online team

- Worked with data gained from the network to be output from the server to the client informing basic telemetry stats.
- Created a filter system for UI to use on notification toasts.
- Generated lists for use in relationship connections between users.
- Passed messages between clients via server while maintaining the individuals' profanity wishes.
- Handled bugs involving the in-game voice chat system.

Call Of Duty Modern Warfare 3

Everything above as well as

- Refactored and cached an old system to improve computation.
- Monitored any issues within voice and client-to-server user communication features, on main as well as asynced, as was within my purview to maintain.
- Worked within UI for bugs that impacted the network telemetry to find trouble points and fix them if they existed on the backend.
- Created touchpoints for UI to tie into, to pass data from and to the server side of the games to the respective client systems.

Call Of Duty Modern Warfare Mobile

 Worked alongside the mobile team to ensure that any features placed into the engine were compatible with any features placed into the mobile executable.

Tools & Skills

Tools

Visual Studio

VS Code Perforce &

Git Source Control

Languages

Java C# C++/C Kotlin Python

Skills

Linux, PC, Mac OS
Command Line
Command Prompt
Ansible Automation
Android Development
MySQL queries & SQL database
Shell & Bash Scripting
Test case development
Regression Testing
Algorithm Complexity Analysis
Data Center Cluster Basics
Elk Stack Monitoring

Education

University of Utah 2023
Bachelors of Science
Computer Science in Games
Utah State University 2016
General Education

Extracurriculars

Joined the 2020 season HackTheU as a club organizer on the marketing team

Volunteered during the 2019 season HackTheU overnight hackathon event

Work Experience

Associate Software Engineer, High Moon Studios

2022 - 2023

- Worked with both my specific engineering team as well as within the multi-studio network to make and improve the player experience for online multiplayer player vs player games in the Call of Duty franchise.
- Worked with multiple discipline teams such as Audio, UI, and server-side teams to create systems as needed.
- Daily studio-wide team 'stand ups' and weekly 1-on-1 meetings with my supervisor to ensure proper progress is always being met.
- Requested and gave feedback to team Swarm reviews to ensure any code going into the system was in a healthy state before submission.

Network Intern, University of Utah

2016 - 2022

- Work at improving personal understanding of Network topologies
- Furthering personal growth and understanding of Linux systems and command-line actions
- · Create and keep records of personal development on relevant knowledge basis' for weekly and monthly sync-ups
- Experience within Android Studio to create a user interface with Raspi3 robot run on UDP
- Trouble-shoot user-level issues within the clusters via Jira, and currently Service-Now
- Spun up resources within GENI Experimenter to create experimental resources with which to test different programs/processes in a safe environment
- Create system logging from the base (grep file), up to the ElasticSearch/LogStash level
- Gathered data via SSH/VC to logs to complete a DoD 5220.22m Nwipe for secure future use
- Utilize company equipment to expedite all job necessities promptly
- Ensure proper care of all company equipment